Bless the bowl. Bless the hands. Let sweetness stand.
Morning in a porcelain cove, sun pooled low,
apricots lanterned in a hush of gold.
Pith and peel, citrus zeal, rind thin as snow,
steam from the kettle paints halos cold.
Plums keep quiet in a bruise-blue hold,
pears hum sugar in a barely-told tone—
fruit is a choir when the lids unroll,
kitchen becomes chapel where the small things glow.
Apricot epiclesis—over fruit and tea,
orange marmalade homemade, bless the peel and seed.
Body of bread the benediction—triangles three,
sweet summer honey bee, sweet summer honey bee.
Toast cut corner-to-corner—three sails bright,
butter like sunlight drifting left to right.
Zest on the knife, a bright sting of light,
marmalade amber with its bitter-sweet bite.
We set down plates like quiet rites,
grain meets citrus, the day sets right—
triangle, triangle, triangle: stay,
hold what is tender in a simple array.
Little crumbs fall like sparks to the plate,
bless what is given, bless what can wait.
Apricot epiclesis—over grain and tea,
orange marmalade homemade, keep the fragrance free.
Body of bread, our benediction—triangles three,
sweet summer honey bee, bring the field to me.
Say the small words we know: thank you, be kind, come home.
Jar with a paper lid, twine tied twice,
sun kept living in its amber ice.
We taste last August in a winter slice,
sour meets sugar till the balance is nice.
Name on the glass in a looping hand,
seed of an afternoon we didn’t plan—
we pass it around like a gentle command:
“carry each other, as sweetly as you can.”
Apricot epiclesis—over fruit and tea,
orange marmalade homemade, bless the you and me.
Body of bread the benediction—triangles three,
sweet summer honey bee… make ordinary holy.
What do we consecrate?
Peel, crumb, heat.
Where does the blessing rest?
Where mouths and memory meet.
Who is invited in?
Anyone who knocks.
What do we keep?
Enough to share from the box.
Knives down easy, kettle sighs done,
marmalade gleams like a very small sun.
We break and we butter, we sip and we see—
mercy is sticky and tastes like tea.
If grief sits quiet at the edge of the cloth,
we slide it a triangle, tender and soft;
let sweetness speak in a language of slow,
and let what we cannot answer go.
Apricot epiclesis—over fruit and tea,
orange marmalade homemade, bless what’s come to be.
Body of bread the benediction—triangles three,
sweet summer honey bee, keep buzzing in me.
This is the sending: wash, warm, share.
This is the keeping: a little light left there.