Everyone’s come to our house today,
But no one is asking me if I can play.
They’re all wearing suits and they’re all wearing black,
Like a murder of crows in a big, noisy pack.
There’s sausage rolls sitting on paper plates,
And people keep talking about "the fates."
The tea is too hot and the kitchen is loud,
I’m looking for her in the middle of the crowd.
But she isn't there in her favorite chair,
She isn't upstairs brushing her hair.
And there are black balloons tied to the garden gate,
Is it a party?
can just..
someone tell me straight..
Why is the balloon the color of night?
When they say everything is "alright"?
I don't really understand,
"sweetheart" they say as they take my hand.
Though we are here,
my aunties,
are left missing.
just a little heart left wishin',
they would be more,
than dads stories.
We went to the park where the grass was all wet,
To a place I'm not likely to forget.
There was a big wooden box with a shiny lid,
I think, I was the only kid,
there at all.
Someone read
She’s as big as the sky,
she’s as big as it all.
They lowered the box down with a rope and a prayer,
Two trumpets played some old fanfare.
An old lady dressed in this guise,
hiding well the tears in her eyes.
I am not sure,
what I am supposed to do.
I have the slightest of a clue.
But dad said,
It's fine to not comprehend,
It's okay to not pretend.
If these balloons go pop,
Will the rain in the living room finally stop?
If I wear my red jumper,
will I be in trouble?
It is very thin,
this dark bubble.
The man in with the collar said,
she’s "in a better place".
I saw not much on his face.
Yeah, there are black balloons tied to the garden gate,
I think I’m not the only one staying up late.
Dad said it's kind of like a "celebration",
but I've this odd sensation.
a way we remember them for who they were,
"this is something that must occur".
And the truth is..
I..
I am not ready for any of this.
There is more than I know,
That I will miss.
Mum...
I’m standing here,
one by one I say goodbye.
just me by the garden wall,
The sun sets and the shadows loom tall.
Maybe I should,
I should,
Shouldn't I..
Aye,
I'm going to give it a try..
one by one I say goodbye.
Just..
So you're not alone..
Bye bye,
little black balloon..