“You always leave on Thursdays.”
“Only so I can come back Sundays.”
Bag by the door, fog on the lane,
Jacket still warm from your hands again.
Train in ten, you're up in my chair,
Drawin’s in my pocket, crayon everywhere.
I brew one strong, your cup's still set,
Your toast half-bitten, I ain't cleaned yet.
You said, “Go then, but don’t be long,”
So I walk through mist hummin’ our song.
Little star sleeps over the ocean,
Little sun wakes over the sea.
Laugh still hums in my coat pocket,
So bring back my Teema to me.
Bring back, bring back,
Oh bring back my Teema to me—to me.
My little fox curled in dreams by the sea.
You forgot your snack, again—what a shock,
Left it on the counter by my polka-dot sock.
I drew you a dragon and taped it to your tea,
So when you're missin’ me, you sip quietly.
Mum says I’m bossy, I say I’m the chief,
Captain of the ship till you’re back by the reef.
I count the sleeps and the Weetabix packs,
You better come back or I’m eatin’ your snacks.
Little sun glows out through the window,
Little fox plays in the breeze.
Elara’s moon waits on the table,
And Papa sails back to me.
Come back, come back,
Come back through the wind and rain.
My Taid with the traincase again.
Ferry pulls out, and I see your face
Drawn on the sky with that space-case grace.
Your voice in my headphones sayin’ “don’t be late,”
And I swear the gulls all carry your weight.
Cuddle up snug, but they ain't the same,
They miss your laugh and your made-up game.
I check my coat—found glitter from you,
Magic’s still stickin’ like glue in my shoes.
Elara sleeps over the ocean,
Teema calls through the trees…
She sings to the wind like a compass,
She sings all the way back to me.
Sleep tight, sleep tight,
My girl sails where she pleases.
Hold fast, hold fast,
I’ll be back before the moonlight freezes.