The rain taps glass, the river sighs,
Cranes reach up to clouded skies.
Under an awning, they take their place,
The city reflected in each other’s face.
The picture blooms, their faces framed,
Raindrops caught like silver flames.
(playfully)
"Do you think the river remembers the ships?
Every journey lost to its fingertips?"
(smiling)
"Maybe it does, maybe it keeps,
Every whisper of where they’ve been in its deeps."
She pulls a camera from her bag,
A flash ignites in the gray and drags.
The photo fades, a ghostly start,
"Wait for it," she says, "it’s the best
part."
The picture blooms, their faces framed,
Raindrops caught like silver flames.
(teasing)
"You blinked—classic you!"
(laughing)
"Perfect imperfection. That’s my cue."
A Polaroid in the city rain,
A fleeting spark they’ll hold again.
Each snapshot fades, but love won’t go,
It lingers like the river’s flow.
The streets are slick, the lights aglow,
Puddles shimmer like worlds below.
She skips ahead, her boots splash wide,
"Catch me if you can!" she cries.
Puddles shimmer like worlds below.
She skips ahead, her boots splash wide,
"Catch me if you can!" she cries.
(calling after her)
"You’ll slip and fall!"
(grinning)
"Maybe I will, but I’ll take you, too!"
He grabs her hand, the laughter high,
A reflection ripples as they pass by.
A Polaroid in the rain-streaked night,
A moment caught in imperfect light.
Each frame a spark, each line a trace,
A fleeting echo they can’t replace.
They pause by the river, the rain turns soft,
The skyline hums, the cranes aloft.
(thoughtfully)
"Do you think these moments stick like glue?
Or are we just shadows in passing through?"
"We’re light in the cracks, the lines in the frame,
The beauty of now, the spark without name.
The Polaroid fades, but the feeling stays,
A timeless spark in endless grays."
She lifts the lens, the rain still falls,
"One more shot before the night calls."
The flash ignites, their smiles collide,
A fleeting moment where worlds abide.
"The Polaroid fades, but the stars remain,
A story of love through the city rain."
She lifts the lens, the rain still falls,
"One more shot before the night calls."
The flash ignites, their smiles collide,
A fleeting moment where worlds abide.
The photo shows two faces bright,
A city wrapped in rainy light.
She holds it close, her voice so low,
"This one’s for us, where love will
grow."
A Polaroid of hearts aligned,
A moment brief, yet undefined.
Each frame a story, though time may
blur,
A spark remains, forever hers.
The rain lets go, the sky turns gray,
They walk the path where rivers sway.
The photo’s safe in her pocket deep,
A memory made, a love to keep.
"The Polaroid fades, but the stars
remain,
A story of love through the city rain."