I’m looking at the glossy finish, staring at the frame,
Trying to find the girl I know behind the family name.
Why are you smiling like that?
Is it 'cause they told you to?
Is it because you were desperate to see this evening through?
You’ve got the floral dress on,
you’ve got the hair done right,
A curated version of a Saturday night.
But I can see the tension in the way you’re holding your breath,
Like you’re trying to charm the sadness,
or flirt with a little death.
You got all dressed up, a proper work of art,
With a velvet ribbon tied around a hollowed-out heart.
But you had no one to dance with,
no one to take your hand,
Just a lonely silhouette in a crowded, noisy land.
I can tell you were trying so hard to make it a "good one,"
To capture a spark before the light was all gone and done.
Did it shatter you too?
Did the glass hit the floor?
Can you fold yourselves into this version anymore?
Sometimes we smile when we’ve got nothing left to give,
A performative,
a habit,
a way to try and live.
Like gravity,
pulls us into a quiet submission,
To the expectations and the family tradition.
It’s a red-shift in that grin,
a stretching of the light,
The further you go,
the less you’re in sight.
Is it real?
Still because the camera lied?
Cute little cuptake, frosting says:
"Hey, at least you tried"
You thought this photograph hid exactly how you felt,
That the camera wouldn’t notice the way you started to melt.
But the red-shift is happening,
the stars are moving away,
And the "you" in the picture is fading into the grey.
I can see you’re forcing it,
the muscles in your jaw,
Trying to obey some kind of unwritten law.
"Be happy, be pretty, make the memory stay,"
While the actual soul of you is drifting out of the bay.
cerebral, mental, odd little temptation,
push to shove, successful migration.
You’re a thousand miles deep while you’re standing right there,
With the smell of the perfume and the spray in your hair.
But the camera is honest, even when you are not,
It captured the vacuum, it captured you right on the spot.
If we could do this again,
without the lens in the way,
Without the "look over here" and the "what will they say?"
Would you dance with me?
Just a spin round the room?
Could we blow out the candles and dispel all the gloom?
Could we just... be a family?
This time, for real?
No ghosts in the kitchen,
no wounds to hide.
Could we be messy and loud,
and genuinely broken,
Instead of these polite words,
politely spoken?
Did it shatter you too?
Did you feel the crack?
When you realized there wasn’t a way to go back?
Sometimes we smile because gravity demands it,
Even if the heart doesn’t quite understand it.
It’s a red-shift in that smile,
a fading of the glow,
The further you go, the less of you I know.
Can you fold yourself into the pieces that remain?
Or are you just a shadow caught in the grain?
It’s real.
The epilogue is the only thing real,
The only thing left that we’re allowed to feel.
Why are you smiling?
I know you didn't want me to know.
Something not to not let show.
So you're polite,
put up with it for tonight.
smile, and just be "all right".
but maybe...
that is easier said than done.
Next time...
Let’s just dance...
For real.