Airey mouse, airey mouse fly over my head
And you shall have a crust of bread
And when I brew, or when I bake,
You shall have a piece of my wedding cake.
Early bitten,
breakfast smitten,
You awake,
Stretching in bed like a homespun kitten.
Oh aye, there she is,
There is my sweet little miss.
Come come, sun’s all up,
Tide is in, so let’s begin.
“Five more minutes, Tad…”
“Oh aye, but only five more.
Better get going to see what,
What the day has in store”
Sweet so sweet,
My feet knows this street.
Knows the brine and salt,
Set on my skin,
The sea knows,
English-oak hair in the wind.
And I know,
Know this little place is ours.
Pesky picky pastry sweet,
Sweet-sour little heartbeat.
I think, you grow here
Little daffodil dear.
By the seals’ slow call,
A saltflower after all.
Lovely little tiny tousled head,
Breakfast served,
Of course in bed.
Aye, this our getaway
By the cove and Willy’s cave.
Two explorers bold and brave.
Stumble into the morning breeze,
Sun high on the tide and seas.
Let us roam now wild and free.
Past the old Watch House,
By the shore this little mouse.
She runs and skips,
Spray of salt on her lips.
“Tad, tad!
Look, that house is made of shells!”
“Hehe, aye little star.
Shall we go inside?”
Narrow lanes in a ribbon of blue,
Doorframes chipped to a kinder hue,
Fish-baskets dreaming by splintered beams,
Sun stitching gold through the harbour seams.
You point at a cat in a painted frame,
Give every gull a proper name,
Count boat ropes, one to ten,
Lose your place and start again.
Baker’s bell and a saffron bun,
Jam-sticky grin in the Cornish sun,
Cream like clouds on a granite scone,
You hum a tune I’ve always known.
Salt on your lashes, light in your laugh,
Sea writes our names in a foamy graph,
And even when the letters go,
The love stays bright below.
Sweet so sweet,
These feet know this street.
Know the brine and the lift,
Of a harbour shift,
Skiff-oars knocking a timbered rhyme,
Ticking the pulse of Polperro time.
And I know,
Know this little place is ours.
Lemon-kissed and pastry-pressed,
Tiny drum of a happy chest.
You bloom where the brine would drown,
Little daffodil in a tidal town,
By the seals’ slow call,
A saltflower after all.
Salt on the brow, salt on the bread,
Salt keeps the tears we thought we shed.
Sea-sweat mingles with the day’s warm light,
Turns every scrape into pearl and white.
What the wave takes, it leaves in kind,
A softer shore, a gentler mind.
Love grows roots in the stony brine,
Breaks through chalk with a quiet spine.
“Tad… listen. The sea is singing.”
[picked mandolin pattern; fiddle answers in lilting phrases,
ripples like sunlight over water, gentle brush of frame rhythm]
Crab lines coiled in a pail of sky,
You squint one eye and you dare them try,
Pebbles pocketed, green, then grey,
We’ll count them home at the end of day.
Cliff-path thyme in a windy prayer,
Gorse sparks yellow in the salted air,
Hand in my hand at the harbour rail,
Watching a gig boat set her sail.
You say, “Tad, when the water goes,
Does it carry our footprints on its toes?”
I say, “Aye, but it keeps, you see,
The little you, safe here with me.”
For here where the world feels small and wide,
You flower straight through the turning tide;
And every tear I couldn’t hide
Turned sweet as kelp in the evening glide.
Sweet so sweet,
My feet knows this street.
Knows the brine and the bite,
And the soft-gold light,
Knows the song in the rigging’s twist,
Copper on the evening mist.
And I know,
Know this little place is ours
Shell-bright laughter, flour-dust hours.
You grew in salt, you grew in sun,
Two hearts knotted and tied as one.
By the seals’ slow call and the harbour wall,
You bloom, you bloom
A saltflower after all.
Sleepy mouse in a tide-rock bed,
Sea hums low while the day turns red.
“Five more minutes?”, aye, take ten.
Tomorrow we’ll roam these lanes again.