sweet heart,
sweet part,
lend me your wind,
lend me you chart.
I've got six breaths,
still full of steam.
I've been far away,
long since seen.
I'm full of anticipation,
it's a strange odd sensation.
mean maybe a wee bit mad,
still at odds with the world me lad.
aye, who's to say this ain't okay.
it ain't goodbye,
just another horizon,
under a different sky.
sweet little heart I don't carry the same,
sweetheart didn't bury your name.
sour old sot,
something's strange is afoot.
some thing settle and clear,
right here,
right here.
think I tossed and turned,
me head til I learned.
learned I'm ain't gonna find you there.
there around the corner of my eye,
stood all small and shy.
why, why.
tell me why.
tell me friend,
can we not pretend.
can we fend,
not only for our little self.
lay your sorrows not on this shelf.
let's see,
what we.
can do together.
sweet little heart I don't carry in kind,
sweetheart never I'll mind.
sour old sot,
something's strange is afoot.
some thing settle and clear,
right there,
right there.
tell me then,
little lovely light.
do you prefer I say goodnight.
tell me cariad,
my sweet heart.
how could I start.
over again.