This one’s for the twitch-eyed crew,
the duvet divers, the “just one more” too.
When the kettle hums and the stars don’t blink,
and your breath is louder than you think—
the tales start stirrin’, the clock goes weird,
and myth walks in like it’s always been here.---
Yo, I met Gwydion in a chip shop queue,
told me lies so slick they turned to true.
Said “magic’s cheap but stories cost,”
so I swapped my dream for a spell half-lost.
Rhiannon rode past on a ten-speed bike,
left hoofprints on clouds and a trail of light.
She said, “Night’s not made for sleepin’, son,
it’s for castin’ doubt and outrunnin’ the sun.”---
Tales for the ones who blink too wide,
who whisper names when dreams have died.
Wrap the night round your shiverin’ bones,
these verses are doors, not lullaby tones.---
Pwyll sold time in a bottle of ink,
told me “scribble your grief before it sinks.”
The moon played marbles with my fears,
each bounce echoin’ lost kid tears.
Threw pebbles in a puddle, saw futures split,
each one speakin’ in the slang I spit.
My pillow’s a cliff where gods won’t climb,
so I write these verses like nursery rhyme.---
Paper crown, broken spoon,
I kissed the stars with a plastic loon.
Came back down wearin’ shadow shoes,
steppin’ in puddles of old taboos.
Met a fox with a bard’s tattoo,
said “Truth ain’t straight — it spirals through.”
My dreams got debt, my yawns got weight,
but I’ll trade you a tale for the ones who wait.---
Tales for the heads that toss and turn,
for the minds where old songs burn.
No sleep tonight, just myths to break,
for every soul who stayed awake.---
Stir the sugar, stir the stars,
count your scars like bedtime jars.
Drink the dark, don’t blink or fake—
This book’s for you. The wide awake.---
And when the rest are gone to bed,
you’ll find the truth they never said.
Under covers, under skin—
The real tales only ever begin
when sleep won’t win.