On this quiet hill where the sunlight spills,
A canvas waits, the air is still.
Paints and brushes, colors spread,
Memories linger where her mother tread.
"This was her place, where dreams took flight,
She painted the world in morning light."
"Papa, was she like me at all?"
"Oh, love, she was you, standing small and tall."
The sea whispers low, the grasses sway,
She kneels by the easel, her heart at play.
Brush in her hand, the first gentle sweep,
A stroke of connection, quiet and deep.
"She’d paint this view, that tree, the sky,
Caught the world’s beauty in her mind’s eye."
"Do you think she’d like this, Papa, too?"
"She’d love it, my star, as I love you."
The brittle brush in a steady hand,
Marks the moment where we stand.
Each stroke a bond, each line a thread,
Linking the living to the loved ones fled.
Oh, the brittle brush, so worn, so true,
Carries her spirit, through me, to you.
Her hands grow bold, the colors blend,
The canvas blooms, her heart begins to mend.
A blue for the sky, a green for the trees,
Her laughter rises on a warm, light breeze.
"She painted with joy, with love so bright,
She’d say the colors sang in the fading light."
"Papa, why do the brushes feel so frail?"
"They carry her touch, her old love tale."
The brushes creak, the strokes grow wide,
A melody forms where memories hide.
Through painted waves and golden air,
Her mother’s presence lingers there.
As evening falls, the colors fade,
The hill is quiet where dreams are laid.
She holds her painting, her eyes aglow,
A story shared, a love they’ll know.
"She’d sit right here, with the sunset’s flame,
And paint the tree she always claimed."
"Do you think it watches us even now?"
"It stands for her, beneath the bough."
The brittle brush in a steady hand,
Marks the moment where we stand.
Each stroke a bond, each line a thread,
Linking the living to the loved ones fled.
Oh, the brittle brush, so worn, so true,
Carries her spirit, through me, to you.
The stars appear, the sky grows deep,
The brushes rest, their story asleep.
On this hill, with the night’s cool hush,
We remember her, through the brittle brush.
"She painted with love, and so do you.
Through every color, her heart shines through."
"Papa, can we paint here again someday?"
"Always, my love, always."
”Always, my love, always.”