## [Verse 1]
I opened up the dome at half past ten precisely,
The seeing index: excellent. No cloud. The air was still and nicely
Quiet — so I ran calibration, each alignment checked in turn,
And wrote the date and time and coordinates in the column marked Confirm.
I swept the arc I always sweep at the beginning of the night:
The sky returned each reference point exactly at its right.
## [Pre-chorus]
The Pleiades: present. Virgo's edge: precise.
I checked the catalog against the open field, then checked it twice.
A hundred fixed coordinates exactly where they stood —
The sky was doing what the sky has always understood.
## [Chorus]
And then I found the coordinate.
The gap in the catalog.
The sky was clear. The seeing: exceptional.
I checked the calculation, checked the log.
*Not present at the stated position.*
*Magnitude: nil. Conditions: ideal.*
I looked at everything else, carefully.
That is what you do. That is what is real.
I logged the absence.
I logged it like the rest.
With the same hand.
## [Verse 2]
At two I tracked the double star in Cygnus through the lens and found
Its separation to the arc-minute, which I logged and wrote down.
The Andromeda was rising; I photographed her face —
Two and a half million years of light, arriving at this place.
The light that left before the instruments I work with had a name,
Still crossing all that dark to find the dome, to find the frame.
## [Pre-chorus]
I noted every object in the sweep. I held the instrument still.
The protocol continued. I continued. I was thorough. I was careful.
The sky does not renegotiate the scope of what you're given —
You calibrate, you log, you sweep, and you keep on looking, keep on living.
## [Chorus]
And I found the coordinate.
The gap in the catalog.
The sky was clear. The seeing: exceptional.
I checked the calculation, checked the log.
The night held still. I held still.
I did not stop the log.
*Not present at the stated position.*
*Magnitude: nil. Conditions: ideal.*
*To be reviewed. Assigned a number. Filed.*
And I looked at everything else,
I looked at everything else, carefully.
because the sky is still full.
Because the sky is still full.
And that is what you do.
That is what you do. That is what is
real.
I logged the absence.
I logged it like the rest.
With the same hand.
## [Bridge]
You should understand the nature of the light.
The light that reaches the instrument is old.
By the time the light arrives here,
the source is what it was —
a very long time ago.
What you are seeing when you look
is the record of the thing.
Not the thing.
This is standard.
This is noted in the protocol.
You note it.
You continue.
You are here to sweep the sky.
The sky is full.
You look at what is there.
## [Final Chorus]
So I noted the coordinate.
The gap in the catalog.
The night held still. I held still.
I did not stop the log.
*Not present at the stated position.*
*To be reviewed. Assigned a number. Filed.*
And I looked at everything else,
carefully —
because the sky is still full.
Because the sky is still full.
And that is what you do.
That is what you do
when the sky is still full.
## [Outro]
I closed the dome at first light.
I filed the conditions as: clear.
I wrote the night's total objects: logged.
Everything listed — present.
One gap.
*Position: clear.*
*Expected object: not found.*
*Not found.*