# The Right and Perfectest Meanes
The air hums low, a whispering thought,
Canvas stretched, her brushlines caught.
Café buzzes, but she’s far away,
Lost in a world where symbols play.
(to himself)
"What stories linger in the curve of her hand?
What secrets unfold in the lines she’s planned?"
Her brush moves slow, a dancer’s grace,
Tracing a serpent with a human face.
Sun and moon in a union bold,
Bound by chains of silver and gold.
(curious)
"What does it mean, the dragon’s tongue?
The wheel that turns where the stars are hung?"
(smiling)
"It’s the circle of time, from whenz it came,
The search for truth, for a hidden flame."
Through twelve gates where riddles gleam,
A sacred path, a golden dream.
Through twelve gates where riddles
gleam,
A sacred path, a golden dream.
Lead to silver, silver to gold,
The right and perfectest meanes unfold.
Colors shift as the story grows,
A phoenix rises where the poppy blows.
She tilts her head, brush held tight,
"It’s ashes reborn in the fire’s light."
Colors shift as the story grows,
A phoenix rises where the poppy blows.
She tilts her head, brush held tight,
"It’s ashes reborn in the fire’s light."
(thoughtful)
"And what of the stone, the one they seek?
Does it live in this scroll, in words they speak?"
"The stone’s not found in the gold they crave,
It’s the heart that loves, the soul that’s brave."
Through twelve gates where symbols play,
A sacred science to light the way.
Lead to silver, silver to gold,
The right and perfectest meanes retold.
Her eyes alight with the fire she stokes,
A story lives in the art she evokes.
The serpent coils where the eagle flies,
An ouroboros of infinite ties.
(to himself)
"She paints a world where the broken mend,
A map of hope, where circles end."
(playfully)
"Are you lost in thought, or lost in me?
The symbols speak if you choose to see."
The dragon breathes, the phoenix sings,
Lost in a world where symbols play.
(to himself)
"She paints a world where the broken mend,
A map of hope, where circles end."
(playfully)
"Are you lost in thought, or lost in me?
The symbols speak if you choose to see."
The dragon breathes, the phoenix sings,
The cycle turns where the fire clings.
"We’re all just living, in our own way,
Turning motes in light, to find the day."
In every mark, a piece of flame,
The right and perfectest meanes remain.
She hands him the brush, his fingers
still,
"Add your mark, wherever you will."
He draws a line where the rivers meet,
A quiet echo, soft and sweet.
She hands him the brush, his fingers s
till,
"Add your mark, wherever you will."
He draws a line where the rivers meet,
A quiet echo, soft and sweet.
(smiling)
"You’ve gilded the stream with a silver gleam,
Now it’s part of our alchemist’s dream."
(to himself)
"Together we build what the world can’t see,
A map of hope, a legacy."
Through twelve gates where secrets hide,
A sacred path where love abides.
Lead to silver, silver to gold,
The right and perfectest meanes unfold.
The brush lays down, the colors blend,
The story told, yet it won’t end.
In every mark, a piece of flame,
The right and perfectest meanes remain.
watches her pause, hand on skin,
A ripple of wonder, a flutter within.
He kneels, eyes wide, her laugther sp
ills,
"feel that?" — a tiny daffodil.
A quiet echo, soft and sweet.
# The Right and Perfectest Meanes
(soft, awed)
"A secret sign, a perfect beat,
always always, soft and sweet."
(gentle)
"The circle turns, the story grows,
A golden future, nobody knows."
Through twelve gates, where hope is
spun,
A sacred path, a life begun.
Lead to silver, silver to gold,
The right and perfectest meanes unfold.