That was a good day, wasn’t it?
Cardiff, the market, the castle… bet your feet are tired now.
Nope! We should walk home! It’s too nice for the bus!
All the way? Up the canal walk? That’s a long one, love.
I’m not scared! And we might see otters!
(chuckles)
Alright then, the long way it is.
Off the train, Newport lights glow,
Feet hit the pavement, nowhere to go.
Day full of laughter, market stalls bright,
Castle stood tall in the morning light.
But now the sun's hanging low in the west,
Still too warm to let the night rest.
No rush, no ride, no need to roam,
We'll take the long way home.
Past the old docks, down by the quay,
Lanterns flicker where the river plays free.
Canal path calls, soft earth, stone,
Water runs quiet where the willows have grown.
She skips ahead, arms out wide,
Counting the ripples, chasing the tide.
Look, a heron! Quiet now, see? She whispers low, pulling on me.
Dragonflies dart where the reeds stand tall,
Minnows scatter by the old stone wall
Owls start calling as dusk takes hold,
Sky draped deep in lilac and gold.
Take the long way, slow and free,
Through the woods, by the sea.
Hand in hand, step by step,
These are the days we won’t forget.
Shadows stretch, streetlamps hum,
Fox darts quick where the brambles run.
She hums an old tune, soft and clear,
A song I once sang in her toddler years.
Bridge up ahead, water runs black,
Ripples break where the otters track.
Dad, do you think they know our names?
Maybe they do, wild things play games.
We stop, breathe in, lanterns glow,
Steps slowing where moonlight flows.
I love this walk, I don’t want it to end.
Some roads never really do, love.
We just keep walking them in our hearts.
Take the long way, slow and free,
Through the woods, by the sea.
Hand in hand, step by step,
These are the days we won’t forget.
Night folds in, stars shine bright,
Breath turns mist in the silver light.
Footsteps softer, the world so still,
Just us, the trees, the air so chill.
Crosskeys passed, lights in sight,
Cottage waiting, warm and bright.
Door swings open, firelight glows,
She kicks off her shoes, stretching her toes.
I pull down a book, pages worn,
She curls up close, safe and warm.
Eyes grow heavy as the firelight plays,
Drifting off slow as the night-time sways.
Take the long way, slow and free,
Through the woods, by the sea.
Hand in hand, step by step,
These are the days we won’t forget.
You’re asleep already, aren’t you?
(yawn)
Mmmh… still walking…
(chuckle)
Goodnight, little star