I saw the land in the evening,
Where the stars their courses go,
And every star, like a lantern,
Guided where the oceans flow
It’s late afternoon, toast crusts on the floor,
she’s wearin’ fairy wings, shoutin’ “war!”
The dog’s wearin’ socks, the sofa’s a fort,
and I’m just a prisoner beggin’ for support.
She crashes down beside me, half giggle, half sigh,
Then outta nowhere:
“Was she scared of the sky?”
I blink — not ready, but I try to stay soft,
Say, “Nah, she loved it. Said the stars were her loft.”
She nods, grabs a banana like a sword,
“she would’ve joined, right? Been on board?”
Aye, she would've.
screens weren’t a thing, way back when.
Was just parks, puddles, the canal path home then.
Now it’s screen time, to get your blocks in a row,
still late night cuddles to let you both know,
Know that I love you all the same,
The perls om my wrist carry your names.
Oi, do stars remember where they’ve been?
Well, yeah they whisper it through your skin.
threads between the stars, the stars you see
held her then, and now you hold me.
We climb the hill where the nettles still sting,
She finds a beetle, names it “Queen Wing.”
“Bet she would've laughed at that too,”
Aye, The same way that you do.
"think I saw you then, just another point of view"
Bet she sees us now, me and you
We roast marshmallows, she throws one to space,
“What happens to love when it leaves a place?”
It hums in your chest, with ache and grace,
It's cares out the rivers in a wethered face.
She don’t know she’s chasin' echoes through trees,
But she’s catchin’ more than the autumn breeze.
Is it okay to miss someone you never met?
Threads between the stars, the stars you see —
You held her then, and now you hold me.
She’s asleep now, curled like a question mark,
glow-in-the-dark stickers flickerin’ spark.
sit beside her, away the time ticks,
Watching some show on the Netflix
No selfies then, just magic spells
Tenby warm with whispering shells.
No book of faces, just rhythm and place.
Ours, yours, then and now.
Again, again - somehow.
A whisper, a song, a soft cheek pressed—
Two hearts humming, one thread in my chest.
So I write these songs like constellations,
connectin' the dots across generations.
She don't need to know how deep it runs,
She just asks the sky, and the stars respond.
Bright star!
would I were steadfast as thou art —
Not in lone splendour hung aloft the night,
And watching, with eternal lids apart.
In one life, you were starlit grace,
A song that brushed across my face.
In one, I died too soon to see
The way your smile could shatter me.
Threads between the stars, the stars you see —
You held her then, and now you hold me.
But always, always, we return,
To ash, to flame, to ache, to yearn.
A thread between the stars is spun
By hands that know what we’ve become.
For we are more than blood and bone,
More than fate or fate alone.
We are the whisper in the storm,
The fire that waits to be reborn.
So if this life we do not meet,
If I walk past you on the street,
Look to the sky, love, call my name.
I’ll find you. I will find you.
All the same.