Platform four, a pneumatic roar,
Think I must have come this way before.
little gold start sticker, in the sunlight flickers,
hardly able to stand, just by this hand.
sundry voice in a concrete hall,
lean the head back against the cold wall.
Too much history, too much to know,
nearly here, almost time to go.
stingly sundry breath
now ticking the clock
of sudden death.
change of pace,
motion blurr
Loud the voices,
as they stir.
no,
its nothing,
close the door.
don't like this much at all,
not any more.
Down in this trench,
all noise is quenched.
Happy, happy
with the volume today.
Aye, come out to play.
shouting out names,
playing games.
The woman is crying,
no, now I am lying.
She just, catches her breath.
mumbles a little something about
life and death.
Like everyone else here,
she's just trying.
prying eyes,
a guise,
just to see us in surprise.
oh no
no not this again
(Sundry... sundry...)
holy, hevenly,
non-being.
fragile all-seeing
god father of well-being.
give me another except,
a quote from the book,
let me have a quick look.
must have mistook,
this,
for self-help.