The mist scuttle off the valley floor
a ghostship passes by the hallway door
Out the window the roots of the oak tree
Say, what do you think it can see?
Feet pressed into the loam
soft little carpeted living room
this fog that lives on our street,
that plays hopscotch beneth out feet,
must be at least a century old.
or so they would have it told.
Aye, it is not so hard to tell
Heard this before and I know it well.
You are sleeping on the sofa here.
Bless you friend, for staying near.
Oh, the clay is thick, we've shaped it well.
Anyone who really looks at this pot could tell.
We really have no need for talk,
setting out on the same old walk.
I’ll take the weight, you’ll take the drag
I'll push the pram, you'll hold the bag.
We hum in tune, brew this strong,
little old ling-a-long.
Aye, it's all but memory now
Strange to recall these days somehow.
Sometimes I think you see me here.
Maybe you know exacly what I bear.
Like to think you keep her warm,
Swear I could weather any storm.
Not for the sake of the afterglow
Not even that I know.
Just do this old work every day,
Now and then fall to my knees and pray.
Pray to this old heart of mine.
Pray for a clear and simple sign.
Oh, the clay is cracked, yet shaped so well.
Who could possibly ever tell.
We have no need for words at all.
Just pull me in when I fall.
I’ll take the heat, you’ll take the stone
I'll keep the blame, you'll lead me home.
We hum in tune, brew this song,
little same old ling-a-long.
And on a simple rainy day,
when I look over at your way.
Even if I don't always say,
Thank you my friend, thank you for today.
Want you to know, what you mean to me.
If you only through my eyes could see.
I'm sure some day you'll understand.
The shapes of holding your hand.
Pour the brew, raise the morn,
above the valley old and scorn.
spil the sun, or let it rain
we'll get through this all the same.
you've got the bags, I'll hold her close
we'll get through the toss and throws.
I’m not alone, I’m not unknown
Frayed at the seems, where you've me sewn.
We have no more need for words,
they skittle away like valley birds.
Just look me in my eyes,
No need for where or whys.
Thank you friend,
I was not alone.
Thank you for comming home.