Count what was kind.
Round to the light.
Carry the one.
Close out the night.
Tiny commits in a daylight repo,
push to the ledger where warm things go.
Rolling hash on the jokes we kept,
normalize breath when the worry crept.
Trailing fears trimmed, tabs to spaces,
pretty-print love in familiar places.
CRC laugh with a salt of grace,
verify vibes at a human pace.
Checksum of the heart, sum the tender parts,
add the quiet touches and the open starts.
When the totals rhyme with the breath you take,
you can rest your head and let tomorrow wake.
Parity bits in a cardigan pocket,
error-correct hugs in a homely socket.
Redundant smiles in a mirrored array,
failover comfort if the light goes grey.
Load balance sorrow on friendly shoulders,
distribute the weight till the night grows older.
Idempotent kindness returns the same,
safe to repeat with your favorite name.
Checksum of the heart, totals warm and clear,
sum of little mercies you allowed this year.
If the figure hums like a kettle’s tune,
you have verified love by the silver moon.
Diff what was said from what was meant,
minimize harm with a calm intent.
Cache the glow for a colder hour,
evict the gloom with a softer power.
Schema of hope with nullable blame,
typed to the real with your given name.
Close the log gently, rotate the file,
heart stays healthy in a smaller style.
Retriable joy.
Backoff of rage.
Circuit of trust.
Turn the page.
Checksum of the heart, let the sum be light,
round up the laughter and the made things right.
If the digest sings in a gentle key,
you are good to sleep and good to be.
May your diffs be small.
May your merges be kind.
May your code of the day compile in the mind.
May your cache hold warmth.
May your errors grow few.
May tomorrow retrieve every good thing in you.
Index the hugs, append the song,
drop the resentment that stayed too long.
Serialize joy in a feathered frame,
stream it to silence, commit its name.
Garbage collect what the grief won’t keep,
free up the memory for gentler sleep.
Backup the breath in a midnight air,
restore at dawn when the light is there.
Checksum of the heart, final line of code,
validate the love on the evening’s node.
If the sum holds true in the body’s core,
we are whole tonight, we can ask no more.
So close the ledger.
Sign with a sigh.
Kindness verified.
Good night.