Label the jars.
Name what you keep.
Sing while you sort.
Store what you need.
Pantry of stars with a shelf for the rain,
keys on the lids so the heart can explain.
Salt for the memory, sugar for grace,
values in rows with a reachable place.
Collisions arrive with a clink and a grin,
lace a small ribbon and chain them in.
Load factor climbs when the seasons expand,
rehash the cupboard with steadier hands.
Index by scent and the year it was found,
order the thunder, keep joy near the ground.
Bloom filter hums at the door like a friend,
no to the clutter that never should blend.
Hold what you hold with a patient map,
name every echo, loosen the trap.
Half hymn, whole hashmap,
label the love, lay down the cap.
Place it on shelves the soul can track,
teach your hands which jars to stack.
Half hymn, whole hashmap,
hum while you file what calls you back.
Back up the warmth to a distant sky,
S3 buckets where lullabies lie.
Version the days with a tidy tag,
roll to a point where the storms unflag.
Redis for sparks that you need real fast,
Vault for the names that were never to pass.
Terraform towels on pegs of light,
Helm charts simmer for soups at night.
K8s cluster of chores that play,
autoscale kindness when guests will stay.
Observability lives in the pan,
golden three signals in one clean plan.
Half hymn, whole hashmap,
keys like prayers in a cotton wrap.
Write what you mean on the circle’s flap,
read it again when the winds clap.
Half hymn, whole hashmap,
store it with care, no need to snap.
TTL on the worry so it fades on its own.
LRU for the grudges, let the oldest be gone.
Circuit breaker on rage till the rhythm is grown.
Backoff and breathe, then come back home.
Schema for mercy with nullable fear,
types that accept every tear.
Map of the kitchen to map of the sky,
same quiet rules for a life lived wise.
Consistency happens in hours, not ticks,
stir till the heart finds a stable mix.
Strong where you must, eventual where kind,
choose the domain that softens the mind.
Garbage collect what was never your task,
free up the memory behind the mask.
Store what you learn in a gentle tone,
helping yourself is how help is grown.
Half hymn, whole hashmap,
sing while you sort, no need to rush back.
Put down the pain in a labeled pack,
fetch only the courage you lack.
Half hymn, whole hashmap,
home is a table of keys and tact.
Query the light, let love enact.