Steam curls sideways, line breaks bend,
cup at the ready, we test again.
Glass keys shimmer, brushes set pace,
code of the kettle redefines space.
I strike the flame with a ritual hand,
water as witness, vessel as stand.
Bubble ascends in a spiral trance,
alchemy whispers in vapor dance.
No theorem steady, no proof exact,
heat folds reason, the edges contract.
Runes in the window, they scatter, they blend,
I follow the pattern but it turns at the end.
Kettle logic, charm of chance,
steam writes verses the glass won’t grant.
Try to parse but the signs collide,
I end in the landscape I keep inside.
Salt shakes memory, copper rim sings,
iron remembers the weight of things.
I stir with a spoon like a wand of tin,
sugar combusts where the cracks begin.
The fog was a script I thought I knew,
yet symbols shimmer and slip straight through.
Instead of a theorem I find my skin,
steam folds inward and pulls me in.
Kettle logic, page runs wild,
smoke like scripture, heat beguiled.
Every formula breaks, applied,
I walk through the threshold of my own heart’s tide.
Lead turns laughter, silver to sigh,
steam burns prayers in a coded sky.
Chalk on the sill begins to fade,
symbols erased by the world they made.
Transmute sorrow, distill the ache,
boil till brittle assumptions break.
In the heartscape’s lab I see it plain,
the yield of the ritual is love from pain.
Glitch in the vessel, spark in the seam,
mercy arrives as an unforeseen dream.
Every parameter fails to hold,
yet something gentler compiles from old.
Kettle logic, alchemy true,
every failed line writes something new.
What I extract is not control,
but the steam of a soul that consoles my soul.
Cup in my hand, the fog drifts wide,
ritual ends in the heart inside.
No law remains, no proof to keep,
kettle boils mercy and sings me to sleep.