Tap tap cupboard, smile on click.
Tiny guardians dance, approve or pick.
Spry little sprites in the cinnamon lane,
apron halos, jam-dot stain.
They run the shelf with a jingle key ring,
audit the spoons when the kettles sing.
Reach for the nutmeg, shelf goes hush,
drawer slides back with a velvet brush.
Pixie in gingham, cheeky and keen,
points at the lips like mind your mean.
Please is the password, thank you the tag,
two factor pantry, now beg just a tad.
Wiggle your toes, tap the floor rag,
laugh once kindly and lift that bag.
Please is the password, thank you the tag,
kindly demons nod and lift the snag.
Auth on the cupboard with a waltzing knock,
time code humming from the copper clock.
Six soft digits in a teacup tone,
one breath window then the grace is shown.
Nonce like a wink so the trick won’t clone,
session gets blessed with a crumb of scone.
OAuth handshake made out of cheer,
kazoo confirms you are truly here.
Cookie in the cookie jar sets your state,
sprinkle of sugar for the small update.
HMAC secret is please and peace,
hash of a grin and a shoulder release.
Greedy grabs throttle with a friendly fine,
429 in chalk on the brine.
Retry later with a gentler mind,
rate limit melts when the heart’s aligned.
Please is the password, thank you the sign,
two factor pantry in skiffle time.
Hum your code and toe the line,
door swings open like it knew your rhyme.
Idempotent scoop for the cinnamon rain,
same sweet measure when you ask again.
Transaction starts when the apron nods,
commit on a giggle, rollback on snods.
Pantry runs sandbox, safe and neat,
tests your manners before you treat.
Exception raised for a huff or brag,
catch with a curtsy, clear the flag.
Recovery codes are patience and play,
backup phrase whispers try kind today.
Root is gratitude, never by force,
grant comes gentle on the wooden course.
Tiny librarians of clove and clink,
index the jars by scent and wink.
They patch your hunger with a hymn so small,
release notes pinned to the spice rack wall.
Heartbeat monitor is the kettle’s beat,
health check passes when you share a seat.
Warm little demons with a ledger of grace,
sign your request with a laughing face.
Please is the password, thank you the key,
two factor pantry for you and me.
Tap tap rhythm and a soft merci,
nutmeg appears like a Jubilee.
Please is the password, thank you the key,
kindly demons cheer and pour the tea.
Cupboard clicks cozy, shelves breathe light.
Auth complete, appetite bright.