In a clear-neck jar a small loop starts,
fed by our warmth and our ordinary arts.
Flour like snowfall, water like rhyme,
the starter learns us one bubble at a time.
Tiny events queue up at the skin,
rise ticks forward, rest ticks in.
The house is the clock and the jar is the node,
wild yeast parses our breath as code.
Leaven, rise, in the cradle of the bowl,
slow compile of a patient whole.
Lift our crumb with a gentle surprise,
fold, breathe, wait, and let it rise.
Palm to the dough and the kernel replies,
threads of gluten wake and organize.
Fold into corners, then yield to sleep,
time does the sorting the hands can’t keep.
We buffer our aches in the linen’s shade,
debounce the fretting our pulses made.
Salt sets the bounds where the edges meet,
a tidy constraint for a living beat.
Leaven, rise, through the queue of the hours,
steady event loop, soft hidden powers.
Lift our names to the warm inside,
hold, turn, rest, and let them rise.
Heat is a signal the stone understands,
transfer and transform in embered hands.
Steam writes a secret the crust decodes,
scoring the surface like tidy roads.
Weights shift closer, the lattice finds form,
entropy tames to a honeyed norm.
What we kept feeding now answers in crumb,
a quiet consensus that hums and hums.
Refine the simple, distill the kind,
filter the bitter, reframe the mind.
From starter to sharing the cycle aligns,
state to new state in gentle designs.
Leaven, rise, for the meal and the meeting,
break us to sharing, mend us in eating.
Lift our table with warm replies,
serve, bless, breathe, and let it rise.
Cooling is counsel the loaf now gives,
soft crack reports how the waiting lives.
I read the console of tiny pops,
each little message as resting drops.
Tomorrow I feed from today’s saved part,
seed value carried like faithful art.
The jar remembers our voice and eyes,
it trains on kindness and learns our skies.
Leaven, rise, in the quiet of our care,
slow bright upgrade of daily air.
Lift this home till the tender replies,
warm, calm, close, and let it rise.