Two black coats on the fence in a row
click click code in the shine they stole
tidy the timeline beak by beak
they log our mornings cheek to cheek
Clack on the rail like a dotted tick
note every crumb every clink every nick
flip of a feather writes date and time
audit in echo and rhyme on rhyme---
Clack if it’s clear, clack clack if it’s late
one clean click for an open gate
feather prints scatter like a little parade
log the love we almost said
Click for a start, click click for a wait
three soft taps for a turned back plate
tie it with wire where the shadows braid
save the smile before it fades------
They pinch a ringlet of foil and light
stash it as proof that the dawn was right
save to a cache in the hazel shade
checksum glimmers in the twig arcade
Page of the day with a glossy sheen
pushed to the cloud of the hedgerow green
branch on a breeze where the records wait
fence as a ledger for a saved state---
When rain writes static across the lane
they buffer the thunder and trim the rain
tell me the line where the light comes through
tick it with beaks in a bright tattoo
When dusk gets heavy and clocks feel slow
they file the hush in a steady row
sidelong shimmer in the paling slate
signed with a glint at the garden gate------
O hey bright thieves of the silver thread
leave me a log for the loaf and the shed
note my laugh on the sill by noon
tag my tea with a tin-cap rune
O keep our secrets but keep our truth
pin them in pairs on the paling smooth
when the hour trips twice and drifts a beat
write it in clicks with your clever feet---
Clack for the promise we nearly spoke
click for the gentle unknotted yoke
two bright thieves with a book of sky
write our yes where the breezes fly
Diff all the hours with a beady eye
merge our mistakes where the fence lines lie
roll back worry when the sky goes slate
restore the warmth to a golden state---
Log our living
Line by line
Pin our giving
Shine to shine
Hold our home in a fence-top slate
Saved by the click of a magpie state