Breath warms the glass.
Feather writes light.
Winter loosens its latch.
I step back into bright.
Small wings sketch routes above the lane,
looping the chill out of my veins.
Footprints melt to a softer grid,
paths recompile from where they hid.
Cold start heart with a match and tea,
bootstrap dawn to a key of E.
Birdsong seeds the barren branch,
call it a patch for a longer chance.
I count slow threes with a palm on wood,
version the hush into something good.
Meandering migration, teach me the turn,
thaw me from pages that forgot how to learn.
I write myself out from winter’s line,
into a margin of yellow shine.
I remember you, daffodil, bright as a bell,
spring in the syllable where I dwell.
Schema of sleep sheds brittle brace,
fields allow sun in a gentler place.
Cache of sorrow clears by degrees,
warm cache builds on the southbound breeze.
Migrations run with a careful script,
rename the rooms where the light has slipped.
Seed data tucked in a pocket of soil,
hands for the work, time for the toil.
Checks on the roots, green health fine,
readiness probes in the crooked vine.
Meandering migration, give me your way,
curves over clocks, breath over sway.
I write myself out of the frost-bit prose,
into a stanza the robin knows.
I remember you, daffodil, tender and true,
gold in the center of everything blue.
State machine heart with a springward edge,
transition names on a meadow’s ledge.
Enter with water, exit with light,
guarded by kindness, validated right.
Garbage collector hums in the lane,
sweeps out the cruft of a colder brain.
Newtable mercy joins to the old,
foreign key laughter, stories hold.
Consistency model soft and kind,
eventually whole in a patient mind.
Meandering migration, widen my scope,
merge me with daylight, annotate hope.
I write myself out where the thaw begins,
into the chorus of tender winds.
I remember you, daffodil, wink of the sun,
proof that a winter can be undone.
Commit small changes to the budding day,
no squash of sorrow, let branches play.
Tag this release with a quiet ring,
changelog reads simply: became spring.
Swallows refactor the sky with threads,
weave back warmth where the gray once spread.
I run the loop till the lungs agree,
timers align with the willow tree.
Heartbeat ticks like a wooden clock,
three-step faith on a mossy rock.
Name the horizon a living file,
open for writing another mile.
Meandering migration, keep me in flow,
teach me the routes only wild things know.
I write myself out from winter’s hold,
into a script that blooms and unfolds.
I remember you, daffodil, always near,
spring is the function that calls you here.