Frame rate low, leaf by leaf, hill renders slow.
Big O patience, green code grows.
Pixel of lichen, voxel of stone,
texture maps woven with wind and loam.
Clock drift kindness, seconds in moss,
time gets fuzzy where roots cross.
I breathe on the bark, the shader replies,
soft-light filter on widening eyes.
Moss matrix, gentle engine, keep me kind.
Slow algorithm, hold the line.
No fast-forward on this hillside spine,
we wait, we warm, we learn to align.
Talk of a cheatcode, thumb-tap fate,
reload a save from a cleaner slate.
Konami craving in a tender ache,
rewind the path my heart once made.
But snapshots blur when the rain sets in,
checkpoints smear, we start again.
Eventual consistency under the pine,
two careful hands, one steady time.
Moss matrix, patient teacher, set the pace.
Slow convergence, softer trace.
Rollback dreams fade out of place,
commit to breath, commit to grace.
Anneal in the cold, then warm by noon,
energy landscape hums a tune.
Gradient descent on a grief-shaped hill,
step size smaller till feet stand still.
Entropy whispers but meaning stays,
stored in chlorophyll quiet ways.
Memory foam of a forest floor,
each fallen thought springs back no more.
I test my pulse on a ring of rings,
age in the trunk where the winter sings.
Asymptote love, never quite done,
closing the distance to everyone.
Moss matrix, long renderer of light.
Scene compiles through day to night.
Patience wins when pixels are bright,
green little proofs that we got it right.
Quantum of comfort, dew bead, dawn,
decohere sorrow till edges are gone.
Planck-small promises, tiny and true,
stitching the lattice from me to you.
Cache in the shade what the noon can’t hold,
release at twilight, slow and gold.
Markov of moments, state by state,
loving again rewrites fate.
Moss matrix, coder of the ground.
Low frequency mercy, round and round.
No secret code to skip the wound,
we grow, we glow, we stay earthbound.
So the hillside loads at a living speed,
moss is the engine, love the feed.
No restart key, no silver cheat,
continue is chosen with patient feet.
Strings breathe out and the forest agrees,
saved state now is a life that frees.