Patch day rhythm, bright sun spin,
pegs on the line, bring that in.
Version bump small, smile wide grin,
maintenance window, let care begin.
Sheets in the basin, spiral flow,
spin state tidy, low heat glow.
Lint trap clear, dryer sings slow,
lint as a linter, let errors go.
Changelog chalk on the pantry door,
v1 point now with a little more.
Hotfix kindness, sweep that floor,
uptime heart at ninety-four.
Cron at noon for a kettle clean,
queues drain gentle, light and green.
Defrag thoughts till the seams turn keen,
toy keys sparkle in the in-between.
Hands do science at a homely rate,
fold, stack, calibrate.
Gravity helps when the towels are great,
entropy bows to a well-kept crate.
Patch day at the cottage, clap on two,
we mend, we mix, we push that through.
Equinox balance, holidays true,
remembering softly with a bright new hue.
Patch day at the cottage, whistle that tune,
sun in the sink and a dancing broom.
Needle in fabric, loop through loop,
graph reconnect on a darning swoop.
Edges align, no thread to droop,
merge without conflict, soup to soup.
Broom at the threshold, grain says yes,
garbage collect all the stony stress.
Cache clear leaves from the stoop’s old dress,
fresh path compiled for the feet that press.
Anniversary sparkle on the window sill,
spin like a planet with a gentle will.
Precession of grief to a kinder still,
we tag those days and we let them fill.
Tests pass quiet in a sunlit stack,
unit of breath, integration back.
Warm wind versioned in a cotton rack,
small green commits in a garden track.
Patch day at the cottage, clap in time,
toy bells shimmer on a jangle rhyme.
We name our losses, we lift that chime,
release a little mercy into summertime.
Patch day at the cottage, soft parade,
bright little fixes in the light we made.
Left hand fold, right hand fold,
backup the warmth so it will hold.
Checksum smile, parity old,
mirror the memory, never cold.
Queue that song, clear that queue,
stitch that pocket, sky turns blue.
Ping that heart, pong comes through,
latency low when love is true.
Apron off, repo clean,
release candidate is evening green.
Sunset notes on a silver screen,
toy keys glassy, crisp and lean.
We write small blessings in a tidy file,
cron for tomorrow at the same old mile.
Socks paired neatly in a nested pile,
physics of care in a cottage style.
Spin-down hush and the fans grow mild,
cooling the day like a tender child.
All systems steady, logs compiled,
we sign the page with a whistle wild.
Patch day at the cottage, clap once more,
we keep the rituals we care for.
Solstice, equinox, sacred chore,
remembrance woven through the floor.
Patch day at the cottage, bright and clear,
new small versions of the same old dear.
Patch applied, light verified,
doorway ready, home aligned.