Tap the chest and hear the hollow ring,
The body keeping count of everything.
I stand before the court of accounts
And lay the story out, to all what it amounts
Weigh it good, weigh it clear,
What cracks the heart, but it's own fear.
Not sin nor virtue, not a judge nor saint.
take the messure of things, small and quaint
featherlight heart, want only its part.
born of the ledger from where shall it start.
Words lodged on the bottom, river stone,
Form of breath and marrow grown in the bone.
Could not tell you why, these choices I made.
Was it due, or to the heart it weighed.
A needle settles, the pivot stills,
Done the accounting of my honest ills.
Cannot claim, this was not I.
Clear as day, bright blue sky.
I close the book, now ledger thin,
This time around, what did I win?
Set, ready, ready to go.
Would do this again,
if you must know.
Close up the shop,
only for today.
Back home, on my pillow
this weary head I lay.