The line thins out to steady hum,
as two axises become one.
Trickly tiny runnel,
warped into a tunnel.
Steady as she goes,
Where it leads,
nobody knows.
What is it, this funny feeling -
ominous onto it's reeling.
steady over the stepping stone.
Seems like someone is there,
certainly I am not alone.
Peel of the dark, frame by frame,
Little guardian angel speaks my name.
Troubled trembling soul at rest,
You have come home now,
You did your very best.
Say - Do you, not recognize my face?
After all, do you not know this place?
Welcome, we have been up waiting
welcome home from your hibernating.
confused and not terribly amused,
I think perhaps, I could get used.
to a warm welcome such as this.
In this place, such boundless bliss.
Even the sun here seems to radiate joy,
What was it again you said Tolstoy?
Iljitjs thought his thoughts
in silent making.
Slow textures render,
hardly baking.
What, what?
Where.. was I just before?
Was there not a door?
What is the matter with me,
How did I come to be..
here..
Certainly I have seen this place,
I know it better then my own face.
Something I have always known,
How could I forget my home.