The ivy frames the archway thick with green,
And in the fern shade, someone half-unseen —
A face that shares my bone and shares my grain,
Smiling like they've always known my name.
No ledger here, no tally and no test,
Just roots and rain and the low hum of rest.
A path closes where the old path fell —
The garden is not strange — I know it well.
Oh, the garden blooms in colours I forgot,
Each flower holds a name, each seed a plot.
We are the ones who walked this ground before —
We are the ones who'll walk it evermore.
Look here, look close, the light is soft today —
We've all come home down this same crooked way.
She bends among the roses with her shears,
Humming a verse I haven't heard in years.
She holds a seed out, hard and grey and plain —
"You'll carry this," she says, "down through the rain.
It's not a grief, it's not a weight to dread —
It's just the thing that blooms when you have said."
The geometry of love is not a line —
It spirals like the ivy and the vine.
I find my face in the bark of the old tree —
We are the many and the one, and we are free.
*(Intricate, rolling fingerstyle picking in major 7th chords, warm and resonant, no reverb)*
The ivy holds.
The root is deep.
A promise made.
A promise keeps.