The paper bird is drunk on the high cold air,
Spinning in circles where the light shines bare.
The world below is small as a dropped seed —
But something in the chest still has its need.
There's a tug behind the collarbone, a weave
Of something that reminds me to believe
In the ground below and all that keeps me here —
Hold on, hold on, the root is old and clear.
I remember hands pressed flat in clay and loam,
The kettle whistle meaning you were home.
The kite string bites across my open palm —
An honest sharpness keeping me from calm.
One cut and I become the weather,
One cut and I unravel my tether.
Let me soar above the winter grass —
But let me land when morning comes to pass.
The kite descends through cooling afternoon,
The air grows warm, I hear the kitchen tune.
I fold my wings and feel the good earth rise —
Not lost at all, just borrowed from the skies.
The string goes slack.
The bird comes back.
The heartbeat sings
Where the silence rings.