The ivy climbs the brickwork, thick as velvet on the wall
I thought I knew this path by now, thought it grew in me somehow.
There’s a bench beneath the willow, scarred by years of rain and rest
offers me some company - it does its very best.
She wears a coat of indigo, the color of the night
Before the lungs were given, before the the word said "be there light"
Her face is like a mirror, polished worn and true.
She smiles back at the shape of me,
unsure what I am to do.
Oh, we are the clay and we are the light
We are the words spoken only at night.
You were my brother in the air
Before you learned to bear the stair
The garden keeps the the roots intact
As petals turns, the ground is cracked.
We meet again, not to judge the fall
But to remember, remember it all.
He brings a jar of honey, sticky gold and thick with bees
He says, "I left this on the shelf, right before the freeze."
I recognize the gesture, the tilt of his head, the way he stands
Like a compass pointing north in foreign lands.
We speak in glances the grammar of the old
such things cannot be said by spoken words.
No need to explain the hunger, or the fear of getting old
Just the warmth of recognition, a real hand to hold.
Oh, we are the pot and we are the dirt
We are all the stains upon the gardeners shirt.
You were my sister in the air
Before you learned to find us there.
The garden finds the honey friends
it calls them here, does not pretend.
We meet again, not to judge the fall
But to remember, remember it all.
Sands are slowly shifting, circles shapes the squares
Shaped by the little act of a heart that cares
Of weight and wind and water, bone and breath and blood
I feel the silver tether tighten, pulling back from flood
To shore.
The dream is ending, pulls the closing door.
we meet again, just like before.
We meet again, not to judge the fall
But to remember, remember it all.