The morning cuts a clean line through the pane,
A room that fits me poorly once again.
I press my heel against the cool wood floor
And try to name the things I'm breathing for.
The geometry is wrong, the corners lean,
I'm remembering the shape of what I mean.
The walls hold steady, daylight fills the shelf —
And I am almost here, almost myself.
The mirror holds a face I've worn before,
More translated now, more opened than the score.
I find the grain beneath the windowsill—
It only asks the quiet press of will.
Below the floor the same warmth turns and burns,
Above the roof the same old wheel returns.
I'm not quite lost — I'm only newly thin—
Learning the old patience of being in.
Hard floor.
Let the glass settle.
Let it hold.