The ceiling of the house in the shape of a cone,
Would talk some more, tongue seems of stone
Air a tad thick, too slow, too cold
Up against the ribs, seems to fit the mold.
Such things never really have a name
Tuesday morning, all same - such a shame.
Better get up before the alarm
Perfer to stay under covers,
next to you, cozy and warm
Ah great, translucent little fate
suddenly solid enought to carry such weight.
The clock on the wall has no hands, just a face
Many things here so out of place.
Aye, geometry all wrong
angles sharp, sides too long
mirror mirror, warped in the glass
Watching the present turn into the past
come into focus, sharp and real
accepting the lot, your given deal.
little dear in the headlight
was this all to bright?
smooth brittle texture, gradient rough
maps of a depth worn out tough.
trembeling splatter torn at the seem
gausian blur of this in-between.
I cant make you out, there in the back
cut me some corners or cut me some slack.
or at the very least show me your face,
tell me you left me a singular trace.
breath are small ghosts
that leave the room,
unhesitating, part into fume.
Bless you, not only when you sneeze.
But so you can them gently appease.
Yup, geometry still strange
tune the function to rearrange
the flux of a beating heart
the ordinary wonderful part
open your eyes, its here, this deal
accepting the lot, accepting what's real
little dear in the headlight
was this all to bright?
few steps to the door
few theps to the porch
Lit by a singular burning torch
could you just come and get some rest
Swear I am not putting you to the test
pacing, bracing yourself for the worst.
wont be the last, wasnt the first.
clear all clear
off you go
i'll se you later yeah,
when your back or so.---
no more time now for chitchat
but sooner or later,
yes.. sweetheart---
I promise you that.