The horizon lines are bending into squares
A rigid grid imposed upon the air
I try to float, but gravity is there
A heavy hand that pins me to the chair
I see the light behind the velvet curtain call
But my feet are rooted in the garden wall
The air is thick with dust and memory
And every breath is work for me to breathe
Oh, the silver cord is tangled in the clay
I want to fly, but I must learn to stay
As above, so below, the circle breaks
I’m trading wings for the strength my spine can take
The light is sweet, the light is pure and white
But I have to walk through the heavy night
Recall the triangle, the point of view
Where three dimensions collapse into two
I held the shape before the clay was poured
Before the heavy silence filled the cord
Now bone is iron and the blood is lead
A vessel shaped by things I haven’t said
The mirror shows a face I barely know
Wearing the skin like clothes I outgrew long ago
The door is open, the threshold is thin
A choice of where the light ends and the dark begins
To slip the knot and vanish in the breeze
Or bind the flesh and plant the heavy seeds
Oh, the silver cord is tangled in the clay
I want to fly, but I must learn to stay
As above, so below, the circle breaks
I’m trading wings for the strength my spine can take
The light is sweet, the light is pure and white
But I have to walk through the heavy night
One becomes three. Three becomes one.
The setting sun. The rising sun.
The weight of water. The weight of stone.
I am the seed. I am the sown.
It hurts to hold. It hurts to let go.
The current pulls. The undertow.
So I tie the knot with fingers stiff and cold
A story waiting to be slowly told
The geometry is hidden in the grain
The pain is just the pressure of the rain
I close my eyes to see the spark remain
But open them to feel the wind again
The coat is heavy, yes, the fit is tight
But I will wear it through the coming night
The silver holds.
The clay is mine.
The line is crossed.
The design.