The kettle wakes the kitchen with a hiss,
Then there is this,
upon my cheek -
a soft little kiss.
The ordinary weight -
of a cup of tea.
This stuff right here,
just you and me.
Rain on the rooftop of the world,
Tiny tangled oaken brown curled.
I've come back into something,
the scene of this.
Right in the moments that I miss.
Am I to know this right, was wrong?
Am I the one who really wrote this song?
Secrets written between the lines,
Find them one by one,
yours and mine.
Tiny feed across the matted floor,
A little figure standing by the door.
Sweet daffodil of mine,
Was this all by design?
Something in the chest still hums a note,
An old and half-remembered antidote —
It calls me to the high, the thin, the free,
Our hearth was lit by you, by me.
Rain on the rooftop of the world,
Little strands round my fingers curled.
The very scent, can I now recall,
Swear, I'd give anything,
anything at all.
Am I to know that I belong?
How do we judge this right or wrong?
Secrets are written between the lines,
Find them one by one, yours and mine.
The kettle goes quiet,
A little riot, a roar,
Miss those days that came before,
But most of all,
of that I miss.
upon my cheek
that little kiss,